Inventory of the R. Freeman Butts papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Lamar Alexander and George Bush, 1991 (Box-folder 375: 2)
- National Education Goals Panel, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 375: 3)
- Bush's summit with governors on education, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 375: 4)
- Political and educational context, 1990 (Box-folder 375: 5)
- National Governors' Association and Council for the Advancement of Citizenship, 1989 (Box-folder 375: 6)
- National Governors' Association, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 375: 7)
- Education Commission of the States, 1985 (Box-folder 376: 1)
- Larry Gerston on public policy-making, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 376: 3)
- Research materials, 1983-1990
  - U.S. Congress, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 376: 4)
  - Federal role in education, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 376: 5)
  - Political alienation and apathy, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 376: 6)
  - George Bush as education president, 1988 (Box-folder 376: 7)
- Larry Gerston on public policy making, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 377: 1-3)
- Public policy course syllabi, 1998 (Box-folder 377: 4)
- Center for Civic Education higher education initiatives, 1992-2001 (Box-folder 377: 5-6)
- Harry C. Boyte, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 377: 7)
- Center for Civic Education and higher education, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 378: 1)
- Writings on liberal arts and civic education, 1991 (Box-folder 378: 2)
- U.S. Bicentennial Commission, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 378: 3)
- Eric Hanushek, 2000 (Box-folder 378: 4)
- Carnegie Foundation, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 378: 5-6)
- Thomas Ehrlich, 1993-2000 (Box-folder 378: 7)
- Lee Shulman, 1991-1999 (Box-folder 378: 8)
- Meiklejohn Education Association and Meiklejohn Integrated LIberal Studies Association, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 379: 1)
- Social Science Education Consortium, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 379: 2)
- National Council for the Social Studies, 2001 (Box-folder 379: 3)
- American Association of Colleges for Teacher Education, 1987 (Box-folder 379: 4)
- Comparative and International Education Society, 1990-1999 (Box-folder 379: 5)
- Council of Learned Societies in Education, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 379: 6)
- Correspondence, 1985-2002
  - Don Warren, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 379: 7)
  - Alan Jones, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 379: 8)
  - Margaret Branner, 1988-2000 (Box-folder 379: 9)
  - Norma Wright, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 379: 10)
  - Bert Burns, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 379: 11)
  - Rilla Hanna, 1996-2001 (Box-folder 379: 12)
  - Jerry Dorfman, 1994-2001 (Box-folder 380: 1)
  - Correspondence relating to Hanna Curator appointment, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 380: 2-3)
  - Carl and Trudy Graham, 1993-2002 (Box-folder 380: 4)
  - Ralph Miner, 2000 (Box-folder 380: 5)
  - Denise Gibson and general correspondence, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 380: 6)
  - Personal correspondence, 1985-2000 (Box-folder 380: 7-8)
  - Arthur Levine, 2000 (Box-folder 381: 1)
  - Teachers College, 1998-2000 (Box-folder 381: 2)
  - Louis Benezret, 2001 (Box-folder 381: 3)
  - Jay Heubert, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 381: 4)
  - Denise Gibson, 2001 (Box-folder 381: 5)
  - Tom Dynesson, 2001 (Box-folder 381: 6)
  - Jim McLellan and Donald Arnstine, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 381: 7)
  - University of Wisconsin, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 381: 8)
  - James LaSpina, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 381: 9)
  - Jerry Dorfman and Rilla Hanna, 1989-1994 (Box-folder 381: 10)
- Center for Civic Education, 1999-2001
  - Indianapolis institute papers, 2001 (Box-folder 381: 11)
  - Board of Directors meetings, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 382: 1-7)
  - Cantigny conference, 2001 (Box-folder 382: 8-9)
  - Social studies methods seminar, 2000 (Box-folder 383: 1-2)
  - Indianapolis institute, 2001 (Box-folder 383: 3-5)
- Teachers for East Africa, 1988-2002
  - History, 2002 (Box-folder 384: 1)
  - Reunion, 2001 (Box-folder 384: 2)
  - Correspondence about reunion, 2001 (Box-folder 384: 3)
  - After reunion, 2001 (Box-folder 384: 4)
  - Barry Rosen and Art Levine, 2001 (Box-folder 384: 5)
  - General correspondence, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 384:)
  - Dissertation by Susanne Nanka-Bruce, 1988 (Box-folder 384: 7)
  - Study by Raymond L. Gold, 2001 (Box-folder 385: 1)
- "Back in the Classroom", 2001 (Box-folder 385: 2)
- Teachers College in Afghanistan, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 385: 3)
- Articles reprinted in Studies in International Education, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 385: 4)
- Correspondence, 2001-2002
  - Carl Graham, 2002 (Box-folder 385: 5)
  - Phil Lange, 2001 (Box-folder 385: 6)
- Biographical materials, 1927-1970 (Box-folder 386: 1-10)
- "A Liberal Education and the Prescribed Curriculum in the American College", 1937 (Box-folder 386: 11)
- Articles by R. Freeman Butts, 1950-1983 (Box-folder 386: 12-16)
- Articles by R. Freeman Butts, 1984-2000 (Box-folder 387: 1-5)
- California Social Science Framework, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 387: 6)
- "The Original Intention of an Establishment of Religion", 1987 (Box-folder 387: 7)
- Lyceum of the Monterey Peninsula, 1989 (Box-folder 387: 8)
- Talk to students at York School, 1988 (Box-folder 387: 9)
- "James Madison: Author of the U.S. Bill of Human Rights", 1989 (Box-folder 387: 10)
- Paper by Steve Tozer, 1993 (Box-folder 387: 11)
- "The Time Is Now: To Frame the Civic Foundations of Teacher Education", 1993 (Box-folder 387: 12)
- Various papers written about the Experimental College, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 387: 13)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1999 (Box-folder 387: 14)
- Appointment as William F. Russell Professor, 1958 (Box-folder 387: 15)
- William Heard Kilpatrick Award, 1975 (Box-folder 387: 16)
- Festschrift, 1993 (Box-folder 388: 1)
- Century Club, 1965-1988 (Box-folder 388: 2)
- On retiring, 1953-2001 (Box-folder 388: 3)
- Appointment papers at Teachers College, 1935-1975 (Box-folder 388: 4)
- Appointments and non-appointments at other institutions, 1932-1959 (Box-folder 388: 5)
- San Jose State University appointments, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 388: 6)
- Photos, publicity, and correspondence about appointments, 1938-1994 (Box-folder 388: 7)
- Center for Civic Education, 1995-2004
  - Conferences, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 389: 1-2)
  - International framework, 2001-2004 (Box-folder 389: 3-4)
  - Visit of Russian professors, 2002 (Box-folder 389: 5)
  - Programs, 2002 (Box-folder 389: 6)
  - Correspondent, 2000 (Box-folder 389: 7)
  - Website, 2000 (Box-folder 389: 8)
  - CIVNET, 1995 (Box-folder 389: 9)
- Correspondence, 1998-2004
  - Charles N. Quigley, 1999-2202 (Box-folder 390: 1)
  - Margaret Branson, 2002-2004 (Box-folder 390: 2)
  - Norma Wright, 2003 (Box-folder 390: 3)
  - Charles Bahmueller, 1998-2003 (Box-folder 390: 4)
  - Roger L. Desrosiers, 2002-2004 (Box-folder 390: 5-6)
- Paper by Roger L. Desrosiers, 2004 (Box-folder 390: 7)
- Correspondence, 2001-2004
  - Susan Clelland, 2003 (Box-folder 391: 1)
  - David Matthews, 2004 (Box-folder 391: 2)
  - William W. Kean and Manny Lerner, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 391: 3)
  - Mary Jane Turner, 2004 (Box-folder 391: 4)
  - Ken Toepfer, 2003 (Box-folder 391: 5)
  - E. K. Fretwell, 2003 (Box-folder 391: 6)
  - Alan Jones, 2002 (Box-folder 391: 7)
  - Tahereh Javidi and related correspondence, 2002 (Box-folder 391: 8)
  - Teachers College, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 391: 9-10)
- American Educational Studies Association, 2003 (Box-folder 391: 11)
- Center on Education Policy, 2002 (Box-folder 391: 12)
- Hoover Institution and Koret Task Force, 2002 (Box-folder 391: 13)
- Melbourne University, 2002 (Box-folder 391: 14)
- "Perspectives on Civic Education in the United States", 2002 (Box-folder 391: 15)
- "Education for Citizenship", 2003 (Box-folder 391: 16)
- "The Context of Education for Democracy", 2001 (Box-folder 391: 17)
- Talks, 1993-1996 (Box-folder 391: 18-19)
- "Moral and Civic Education in Current Politics", 2003 (Box-folder 392: 1-2)
- Notes and research materials, 2001-2004
  - George W. Bush inauguration, 2001 (Box-folder 392: 3)
  - National education plan, 2001 (Box-folder 392: 4)
  - No Child Left Behind Act, 2002 (Box-folder 392: 5)
  - Supreme Court, 2002 (Box-folder 393: 1)
  - Vouchers, 2002 (Box-folder 393: 2)
  - Morality and religion in government, 2003 (Box-folder 393: 3)
  - Pledge of allegiance, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 393: 4)
  - Patriotism, security, and liberty, 2002 (Box-folder 393: 5)
  - Affirmative action, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 393: 6)
  - Charter schools and home schooling, 2002-2004 (Box-folder 393: 7)
- R. Freeman Butts Institute of Civic Learning in Teacher Education, 2003 (Box-folder 393: 8)
- Center for Information and Research on Civic Learning and Engagement, 2003 (Box-folder 393: 9)
- Congressional Conference on Civic Education, 2003 (Box-folder 393: 10)
- International Conference on Civic Education Research, 2003 (Box-folder 393: 11)
- Notes and research materials, 2001-2004
  - Iraq, 2002-2004 (Box-folder 394: 1)
  - Afghanistan, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 394: 2-6)
- Teachers for East Africa, 1961-2004
  - Notes, 1961 (Box-folder 395: 1)
  - Writings and clipping, 1961-1984 (Box-folder 395: 2)
  - Peace Corps, 1964-2002 (Box-folder 395: 3)
  - General, 2002 (Box-folder 395: 4)
  - Follow up, 2002-2004 (Box-folder 395: 5)
  - History, 2002 (Box-folder 395: 7)
- Correspondence, 2002-2004
  - Joe Braun, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 396: 1)
  - Denise Gibson, 2002 (Box-folder 396: 2)
  - Denise Gibson and Kim Sebaly, 2003 (Box-folder 396: 3)
  - Steve Tozer, 2002-2004 (Box-folder 396: 4)
  - Carol Graham, 2003 (Box-folder 396: 5)
  - Mike Sapir, 2003 (Box-folder 396: 6)
  - Diane Ravitch, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 396: 7)
  - Gena Phenix, 2003 (Box-folder 396: 8)
  - Michael P. Wolfe, 2003 (Box-folder 396: 9)
- John Dewey, 2003 (Box-folder 396: 10)
- Presentation by Denise Gibson, 2002 (Box-folder 396: 11)
- Content of Our Character Project, 2004 (Box-folder 396: 12)
- Teachers College foundations, 1940-2003 (Box-folder 396: 13)
- Study by Craig Kridel, 2002 (Box-folder 396: 14)
- Video recording of interview with R. Freeman Butts, 2003 (Box-folder 397: 1)
- CD-ROM of lecture by R. Freeman Butts, 2001 (Box-folder 397: 2)
- Photographs, 1945-2003 (Box-folder 397: 3-11)
- Audio cassettes with recordings of Leadership Symposium, 1995 (Box-folder 398: 1-3)
- Video recordings of We the People programs, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 398: 4-6)
- Video recording of Learning Communities program, 1994 (Box-folder 398: 7)
- Floppy disks containing writings by R. Freeman Butts, 1996-2004 (Box-folder 398: 8-17)
- Photograph depicting R. Freeman Butts and Lyndon Johnson, 1966 (Box-folder 399: 1)
- Genealogy, 2002 (Box-folder 399: 2)
- Personal records, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 399: 3-4)
- Student papers, 1947-1929 (Box-folder 399: 5-6)
- Miscellaneous writings and correspondence, 1965-1985 (Box-folder 399: 7-8)
- Doctoral diploma, 1935 (Box-folder 399: 9)